yorkshire is full of incredible things
to do welcome to watchzilla today we are
going to discover the sprawling county
of england yorkshire
whether you want to take in a little
culture visit a historic castle or
explore the many natural wonders that
have helped to give god's own country
its name you're absolutely spoilt for
choice
it's also home to york minster the
largest medieval church in england
a handy hop-on hop-off sightseeing bus
takes in most of the major points of
interest to tourists
number 10 yorkshire sculpture park
focusing on modern and contemporary
sculpture
in a beautiful setting that will see you
enjoying the great outdoors while you
take in the arts
yorkshire sculpture park has more than
earned its place in this list one of
england's most impressive collections of
sculpture is scattered across the
formidable 18th century estate of breton
park
200 odd hectares of lawns field and
trees
a bit like the art world's equivalent of
a safari park
the yorkshire sculpture park showcases
the work of dozens of sculptors both
national and international
the park is partly a homage to local
heroes barbara hepworth who was born in
wakefield and henry moore
though more of their works are on
display at the hepworth wakefield
with so much to see it's perfect for
days out and you'll probably find
yourself wanting to come back
number 9 malham cove needless to say
some of best days out in yorkshire will
see you venturing into the countryside
in search of natural beauty spots
and malam cove is one that you should
certainly hunt out
north of mallam village a 0.75 mile
field walk beside a lovely babbling
stream
leads to malham cove a huge amphitheater
lined with 80 meter high vertical cliffs
whether you marvel at malam cove from
the bottom of its cliff or admire the
view from its limestone pavement you are
sure to be impressed by this yorkshire
dale's landmark
a large glacial waterfall once tumbled
over this cliff but it dried up hundreds
of years ago
this limestone scar is awesome to see
and it's surrounded by beauty sports
that helped to create one of the most
popular walks in the yorkshire dales
visit janet's foss waterfall gordale
scar and malham tarnall in one leisurely
walk
as you cover over seven miles passing
stunning scenery every step of the way
you can hike up the steep steps on the
left-hand side of the cove to see the
extensive limestone pavement above the
cliffs
a filming location in harry potter and
the deathly hallows
number eight clifford's tower the last
vestige of york castle
clifford's tower is now one of the
city's most iconic landmarks
perched on a grassy mound overlooking
the river house
located between fisher gate and
skeldergate bridge york castle was built
of wood by the normans in 1068
the oldest remaining part is clifford's
tower constructed in the 13th century as
a replacement for the wooden fortress
although the castle was originally built
by william the conqueror in 1069
the present-day tower was erected
between 1245 and 1269 by henry iii
when the fortress was rebuilt in stone
and has served numerous purposes
throughout its long history
it was named after roger de clifford
executed here in 1322 as leader of the
lancastrian party
the tower was also infamous as the place
where the king would put those he had
executed on display
even now hundreds of years later it's
still a stunning example of a modern
bailly castle and you can explore it at
your leisure
visiting the rooms that once housed the
old royal exchequer and treasury
as well as climbing to the top of the
tower where you'll be treated to
panoramic views over the city
picnic facilities are available along
with a gift shop
it's definitely one of the more
memorable places to visit in yorkshire
and the kids will love it as much as you
number seven skipton castle what makes
skipton castle so fascinating is its
splendid state of preservation
providing a striking contrast to the
ruins you'll see elsewhere
skipton castle is a medieval castle
built in 1090 by robert de ramil
located in skipton north yorkshire 900
years old and still going strong
skipton castle has become one of the
market town's most popular attractions
tempting folken to explore one of the
best preserved medieval castles in
england
although it is lauded as one of the best
preserved medieval castles in england
many of its most memorable features date
to tudor times
the entire building is open to the
public giving you the chance to explore
everything from the dungeons to the
watchtower
the bed chambers and the bogs entrances
through the original norman archway
which leads to a tudor courtyard with a
u tree planted by lady anne clifford in
and beyond that a warren of rooms to
explore as you can imagine
it's extremely popular with the little
ones so if you're looking for things to
do in yorkshire with the kids
you're onto a winner here grab the
informative free illustrated guide to
the castle from the ticket office
available in several languages number
six
the hepworth wakefield part of the
yorkshire sculpture triangle the
hepworth should sit high on your list of
attractions to visit
west yorkshire's standing in the
international arts scene got a boost in
2011 when the yorkshire sculpture park
was joined by this award-winning gallery
of modern art
housed in a stunningly angular building
in the banks of the river colder
one of the most impressive exhibition
spaces outside of london
the hepworth's architecture is just as
spectacular as the collections housed
inside
not only is it massive with 1 600 square
meters of space dedicated to exhibitions
but it's also filled with exceptional
works of art
the gallery has been built around the
works of wakefield born sculptor barbara
hepworth
perhaps best known for her work single
form which graces the un headquarters in
new york
wakefield's collection includes pieces
from the likes of henry moore harold
gilman and ben nicholson
while the hepworth family gift offers up
rarely seen works by barbara hepworth
from whom the gallery takes its name
look out for the gods collection 2 it
documents 200 yorkshire villages
towns and cities through pictures
watercolors drawings and prints
number five the deep one of the best
places to visit in yorkshire if you've
got kids
the deep will take you into the depths
of its underwater world
introducing you to an array of marine
life along the way
hull's biggest tourist attraction is the
deep britain's most spectacular aquarium
housed in a colossal angular building
that appears to lunge above the muddy
waters of the hummer like a giant
shark's head
arguably the best aquarium anywhere in
the uk the deep is unique
in that it was built specially to help
drive up holes tapering tourist trait as
well as to support marine conservation
inside it's just as dramatic with
echoing commentaries and
computer-generated interactive displays
that guide you through the formation of
the oceans
the evolution of sea life and global
conservation issues
from sharks and sawfish to penguins
jellyfish and stingrays
you'll find all the coolest creatures
within as you pass through clear tunnels
giving you 360 degree views now it's one
of the most visually striking and
popular attractions in the north
with several living exhibitions and
thousands of species on display
including seven types of sharks add to
this a host of exhibits that make
learning fun
a soft play area and a restaurant and
you're all set for a great day out
number four fountains abbey the world
heritage site and with good reason
fountains abbey and studly royal water
garden is a beautiful spot to spend the
day
fountains abbey is one of the largest
and best preserved ruined cistercian
monasteries in england
it was once one of the richest in europe
and it's still beautiful today
offering a unique glimpse into the past
the alluring and strangely obsessive
water gardens of the studly royal estate
were built in the 18th century to
enhance the picturesque ruins of 12th
century fountains abbey
together they present a breathtaking
picture of pastoral elegance and
tranquility that have made them a unesco
world heritage site and the most visited
of all the national trusts paid to enter
properties
this combined with the studly royal
water garden fountains hall and mill
as well as the deer park and orchard to
create one of the best days out in
yorkshire
number three castle howard stately homes
may be two a penny in england but you'll
have to try pretty damn hard to find one
as breathtakingly stately as castle
howard a work of theatrical grandeur and
audacity
set in the rolling halardian hills an
easy 30-minute drive northeast of york
is majestic castle howard
an 18th century house that's full of
history surrounded by 1 000 acres of
stunningly landscaped grounds
ripe for exploring it's no wonder castle
howard is one of the most popular
attractions in yorkshire
built in the 17th century for charles
howard the third earl of carlisle
much of the castle's striking design was
the work of architect john van bra
and the stately home with its central
domed cupola sculpted pillisters and
elaborate frescoes took over 100 years
to complete
this is one of the world's most
beautiful buildings instantly
recognizable from its starring role in
the 1980s tv series brides had revisited
and in the 2008 film of the same name
inside it's not only beautiful but also
full of stories that you can learn as
you wander around
while outside walled gardens woodlands
temples lakes and fountains are just
waiting to be discovered
its many elegant rooms contain paintings
and carvings
period furniture and costumes as well as
valuable vases and statues
the grounds are on a scale to match the
house with an impressive family
mausoleum
an obelisk a pyramid and the lovely
temple of the four winds
and of course there's the spectacular
fountain at the front of the mansion
perfect for the ultimate selfie today
the palatial building is open to the
public by guided tour
and exploring the interiors unveils a
trove of period decor
antique furnishings and fine china a
notable highlight is the castle's vast
art collection
including paintings by van dijk rubens
tinturetto cameletto and reynolds
a portrait of henry viii and an array of
personal works by the ninth earl of
carlisle
feeling puckish there are no less than
three great cafes on site
each serving a wonderful afternoon tea
it's great day out and once the kids
will enjoy as much as you
number two york minster if this stunning
architecture you're after a trip to york
minster is a no-brainer
york minster is the largest medieval
cathedral in northern europe
and one of the world's most beautiful
gothic buildings
built between 1220 and 1472 it's
beautiful to behold and has plenty to
offer visitors beyond simply gazing on
its stunning exterior
imposing york minster the cathedral and
metropolitical church of saint peter in
york in full
commemorates the monks who converted
those living in the surrounding
countryside to christianity
seat of the archbishop of york primate
of england it is second in importance
only to canterbury
seat of the primate of all england the
separate titles were created to settle a
debate over the true center of the
english church
dedicated to saint peter york minster's
bishops even sat on the council at arles
in ad314
after this little is known until ad627
when the oldest documented church was
built here for the baptism of king edwin
of northumbria
succeeding saxon and norman
constructions were destroyed and the
present
cathedral was built in the gothic style
in the 13th century
inside you can enjoy a guided tour take
a trip up the 275 steps to the top of
the central tower
where the views are simply exceptional
or even venture into the chambers
beneath the minster to explore their
latest addition
revealing york minster in the undercroft
definitely one of the best days out in
yorkshire
a highlight of a tour is seeing the
minster's impressive stained glass
windows
most notably the pilgrimage window
dating from about 1312
resting above a stunning dragon's head
the window depicts peter surrounded by
pilgrims along with unusual details
such as the funeral of a monkey note
that the choir east end and undercroft
close in preparation for evening service
around the time of last admission
before we continue be sure to subscribe
to our channel and ring the bell to get
notified about our latest videos
number one national railway museum take
a trip
back in time at the national railway
museum where they have millions of
artifacts ranging from photos to coins
and uniforms
as well as some of the biggest
locomotives in history the national
railway museum has an impressive array
of locomotives and carriages dating from
1820 to the present day
york's national railway museum the
biggest in the world
with more than 100 locomotives is well
presented and crammed with fascinating
stuff
it is laid out on a vast scale and is
housed in a series of giant railway
sheds
allow at least two hours to do it
justice from the shinkansen the only
japanese bullet crane outside of japan
to the eurostar
the fastest train in the uk there are
some amazing machines here
as well as a few with royal links like
queen victoria's palace
on wheels among the many exhibits in the
great hall
laid out like an old-fashioned railway
station are a victorian mail train from
and turn of the century freight and
steam trains and luxurious edwardian
pullman carriages
the museum also now includes a high-tech
simulator experience of riding on the
mallard
which set the world speed record for a
steam locomotive in 1938.
if possible try to time your visit to
coincide with one of the daily
demonstrations of the facility's vintage
turntable for an up-close look at how
these massive machines were turned
around
admire the collection of royal trains
and allow your children to explore the
carriages
free admission makes this attraction the
best thing to do for free in york
do you agree with our picks check out
this other recent clip from watchzilla
and be sure to subscribe and ring the
bell to be notified about our latest
videos